[music]
Welcome everybody and welcome to those
of you joining us on live stream um to
this conversation that I have to say I
have been looking forward to for months.
Uh, I had was lucky enough to ch to
moderate a conversation between Dar
Amade and Demis Hassabis last year in
Paris. Um, which I'm afraid got most
attention for the fact that you two were
squashed on a very small love seat
[laughter] while I sat on an enormous
sofa which was probably my screw- up.
But I said at that point that this was
for me like, you know, chairing a
conversation between the Beatles and the
Rolling Stones. And you have not had a
conversation on stage since. So this is,
you know, the sequel. the the the you
know the bands get together again. I'm
delighted. You need no introduction. Uh
the title of our conversation is the day
after AGI which I think is perhaps
slightly getting ahead of ourselves
because we should probably talk about
how quickly and easily we will get there
and I want to do a bit of a sort of
update on that and then talk about the
consequences. So firstly on the timeline
Dario you last year in Paris said we'll
have a model that can do everything a
human could do at the level of a Nobel
laureate across many fields by 2627.
we're in 26. Uh do you still stand by
that timeline?
>> So, you know, it's always hard to know
exactly when something will happen, but
but I don't I don't think that's going
to turn out to be that far off. So, um
you know, the the the mechanism whereby
I imagined it would happen is that we
would make models that were good at
coding and good at AI research and we
would use that to produce the next
generation of model and speed it up to
create a loop that would that would uh
increase the speed of model development.
we are now in terms of you know the
models that write code I have engineers
within enthropic who say I don't write
any code anymore I just I just let the
model write the code I edit it I do the
things around it I think I don't know we
might be 6 to 12 months away from when
the model is doing most maybe all of
what SWES do end to end and then it's a
question of how fast does that loop
close not every part of that loop is
something that can be sped up by AI,
right? There's like chips, there's
manufacturer of chips, there's training
time for the model. So, it's, you know,
I I think there's a lot of uncertainty.
It's easy to see how this could take a
few years. I don't I I it's very hard
for me to see how it could take longer
than that. Um, but if if I had to guess,
I would guess that this goes faster than
people imagine. That that key element of
code and increasingly research going
faster than we imagine. that's going to
be the key driver. It's it's really hard
to predict again how much that
exponential is going to speed us up, but
but something fast is going to happen.
>> So, you demis were a little more
cautious last year. You said a 50%
chance of a system that can exhibit all
the cognitive capabilities humans can by
the end of the decade. Um, clearly in
coding, as Dario says, it's been
remarkable. What is your sense of do you
stand by your prediction and what's
changed in the past year? Yeah, look, I
I I I think I'm still on the same kind
of timeline. I think there has been
remarkable progress, but I think some
areas of uh uh um kind of engineering
work, coding, or so you could say
mathematics are a little bit easier to
see how they would be automated partly
because they're verifiable what the
output is. Um some areas of natural
science are much harder to do than that.
You won't necessarily know if the
chemical compound you've built or this
prediction about physics is correct. it
may be you may have to test it
experimentally and that will all take
longer. So uh I also think there are
some missing capabilities at the moment
uh in terms of like not just solving
existing conjectures uh or existing
problems but actually coming up with the
question in the first place or coming up
with the theory or the hypothesis. I
think that's much much harder and I
think that's the highest level of
scientific creativity and it's not
clear. I think we will have those
systems so I don't think it's impossible
but I think there may be one or two
missing ingredients. Um, it remains to
be seen how, you know, first of all, can
this self-improvement loop that we're
all working on actually close without a
human in the loop? I think there are
also risks to that with to that kind of
system, by the way, which we should
discuss, and I'm sure we will. But the
the but but that could speed things up
if that kind of system does work.
>> We'll get to the risks in a minute. But
one other change I think of the past
year has been a kind of change in the
pecking order of the race, if you will.
This time a year ago, we just had the
Deepseek moment and everyone was
incredibly excited about what happened
there and there was still a sense, you
know, that Google Deep Mind was kind of
lagging open AI. I would say that now uh
it's looking quite different. I mean,
they've declared code red, right? Um
it's been quite a quite a year. So, talk
me through what specifically you've been
surprised by and how well you've done
this year and whether you think and then
I'm going to ask you about the lineup.
Well, look, I I think we were I was
always very confident we uh would get
back to sort of the top of the the
leaderboards and and the soda type of
models across the board because I think
we've always had like the deepest and
broadest research bench and it was about
kind of marshalling that all together
and um getting the intensity and focus
and the kind of startup mentality back
to the whole organization and it's been
a a lot of work and um but I think we're
and we're still a lot of work to do um
but I think you can start seeing the the
the the the you know the the kind of um
the progress that's been made in both
the models with Gemini 3 but also uh on
the product side with Gemini app getting
increasing uh market share. So I feel
like uh we're making great progress um
but there's a ton more work to do um and
you know we're bringing to bear Google
deep mind's kind of like the engine room
of Google where we're getting used to um
shipping our models more quickly into
the product surfaces. One question for
you Daria on on this aspect of it
because you've just or you're in the
process of you know a new round at an
extraordinary evaluation too. Um but you
are unlike Dennis a let's call it an
independent model maker and there is I
think an increasing concern that the
independent model makers will not be
able to continue for long enough until
you get to where the revenues come in.
Um it's made very openly about open AI
but talk me through how you think about
that and then we'll get to the AGI
itself. Yeah, I mean that you know I
think I think I think how we think about
that is you know as we've built better
and better models. There's been a kind
of exponential relationship not only
between how much compute you put into
the model and how cognitively capable it
is but between how cognitively capable
it is and how much revenue it's able to
generate. So our revenues grown 10x in
the last three years from 0 to 100
million in 2023, 100 million to a
billion in 2024 and 1 billion to 10
billion in 2025. And so th those revenue
numbers, you know, I don't know if that
curve will literally continue. It would
be crazy if it did. Um, but those
numbers are starting to get not too far
from, you know, the sca the scale of the
largest companies in the world. So
there's there's there's always
uncertainty. You know, we're trying to
bootstrap this from nothing. It's it's a
crazy thing, but but I have confidence
that if we're able to produce the best
models in the things that we focus on,
um, uh, then I think then I think things
will go well. And you know I I will I
will generally say you know I think I
think it's been a a good year for both
both Google and Anthropic. And I think
the thing we actually have in common is
that they're you know they're both kind
of kind of kind of companies that are
you know or the research part of the
company that are kind of led by
researchers who focus on the models who
focus on solving important problems in
the world right who have these kind of
hard scientific problems as a as a north
star. and and and I think those are the
kind of companies that are going to
succeed going forward and you know I
think I think we share that between us
>> very much. Uh I'm I'm going to resist
the temptation to ask you what will
happen to the companies that are not led
by researchers [laughter]
uh because I know you won't answer it.
But let's then go on to uh the
predictions area now and this we are
supposed to be talking about the day
after AI. But let's talk about closing
the loop. This the odds that you will
get models that will close the loop and
be able to you know power themselves if
you will because that's the really the
crux for the the winner takes all
threshold approach. Do you still believe
that we are likely to see that or is
this going to be much more of a normal
technology where followers and catchup
can can compete?
>> Well, look, I definitely don't think
it's going to be a normal technology.
So, I mean, there are aspects already
that as Dario mentioned that it's
already helping with our coding and and
some aspects of research. The full
closing of the loop though, I think is
an unknown. I mean, I think it's
possible to do. you may need AGI itself
to be able to do that in some domains
again where there these domains you know
where there's there's more messiness
around them it's not so easy to verify
your answer very quickly um there's kind
of MP hard domains so as soon as you
start getting more and you know I also
include by the way for AGI physical AI
robotics working all of these kind of
things and then you've got you know
hardware in the loop uh that may uh
limit how fast the self-improvement
systems can work but I think in coding
and mathematics and these kind areas. I
can definitely see that working. And
then the question is more theoretical
one is what is the limit of engineering
and maths uh to solve uh the natural
sciences. Darren, you um last year, I
think it was last year that you
published Machines of Love and Grace um
which was a very I would say upbeat
essay about the potential that that you
were going to see unfold and you were
talking about you know a a what was it a
genius of data country
data center I'm told that you are
working on an update to this a new essay
so you know wait for it guys it's not
out yet but it is coming out but perhaps
you can give us a sort of a sneak
preview of what a year later your big
take is going to be.
>> Yes. So, you know, my take my take has
not changed. It has always been my view
that, you know, AI is going to be
incredibly powerful. I think Demis and
I, you know, kind of agree on that. It's
just a question of exactly when um uh
and because it's incredibly powerful, it
will do all these wonderful things like
the ones I talked about in Machines of
Loving Grace. It, you know, will help us
cure cancer. It may help us to eradicate
tropical diseases. It will help us
understand understand the universe. but
that there are these, you know, immense
and grave risks that, you know, not that
we can't address them. I'm not a doomer,
but but that, you know, we we we we we
need to think about them and we need to
address them. And I wrote Machines of
Loving Grace first. I' I'd love to give
some uh a sophisticated reason why I
wrote that first, but it was just that
the the positive essay was easier and
more fun to write than than the negative
essay. Um, so, you know, I finally spent
some time on vacation and I was able to
write an essay about the risks. And even
when I'm writing about the risks, um, I
I I try, you know, I I I'm like an
optimistic person, right? So even as I'm
writing about these risks, I I I wrote
about it in a way that was like, how do
we overcome these risks? How do we have
a battle plan to fight them? And and and
the way I the way I framed it was, you
know, there's this scene from Carl
Sean's Contact, the movie version of it,
where, you know, they they kind of
discover alien life and this
international panel that's like
interviewing um uh you know, people to,
you know, to be humanity's
representative to meet the alien. Um uh
and uh one one of the questions they ask
one of the candidates is, you know, if
you could ask the aliens anyone
question, what it would what what what
would it be? And one of one of the
characters says,"I would ask,"How did
you do it? How did you manage to get
through this technological adolescence
without destroying yourselves? How did
you make it through?" And and and ever
since I saw it was like 20 years ago, I
think I saw that movie. It's kind of
stuck with me. And that that's the frame
that I used, which is which is that, you
know, we we're we're we are knocking on
the door of these incredible
capabilities, right? the the ability to
build basically machines out of sand,
right? I think I think it was inevitable
that the instant we started working with
fire. Um uh but but how we handle it is
is not inevitable. And so I think the
next few years we're going to be dealing
with, you know, how do we keep these
systems under control that are highly
autonomous and smarter than any human?
How do we make sure that individuals
don't misuse them? Right? I have worries
about things like bioteterrorism. How do
we make sure that nation states don't
misuse them? That's why I've been so
concerned about, you know, the CCP,
other authoritarian authoritarian
governments. What are the economic
impacts? Right? I've talked about labor
displacement a lot. And and you know,
what what haven't we thought of which
which in many cases, you know, maybe may
be the the hardest thing to deal with at
all. Um so, you know, I I'm I'm thinking
through how to address those risks. And
you know, for for each of these, it's a
mixture of things that we individually
need to do as as leaders of the of of of
the companies and that we can do working
together. And then there there's going
to need to be some role for wider
societal institutions like the like the
government in in in addressing all of
these. But, you know, I I I just feel
this urgency that, you know, every day,
you know, there's there's all kinds of
crazy stuff going on in the outside
world, outside AI, right? Um but but you
know my my my view is this is happening
so fast and is such a crisis we should
be devoting almost all of our effort to
thinking about how to get through this.
>> So I can't decide whether I'm more
surprised that you a take a vacation b
when you take a vacation you think about
the risks of AI and c that your essay is
framed in terms of are we going to get
through the technological adolescence of
this technology without destroying
ourselves. So, I'm my head is slightly
spinning, but you then and I can't wait
to read it, but you you you mentioned
several areas that can guide the rest of
our conversation. Let's start with jobs
um because you actually have been very
outspoken about that and I think you
said that half of entry- level white
collar jobs could be gone within the
next one to five years. But I'm going to
turn to you Demis because so far we
haven't actually seen any discernable
impact on the labor market. Um, yes,
unemployment has ticked up in the US,
but all of the kind of economic studies
I've looked at and that we've written
about suggest that this is overhiring
post pandemic, that it's really not
AIdriven. If anything, people are hiring
to build out AI capability.
Do you think that this will be as you
know economists have always argued that
it's not a lump of labor fallacy that
actually there will be new jobs created
because so far the evidence seems to
suggest that? Yeah, I mean I I think in
um the near term that is what will
happen. The kind of normal evolution
when a breakthrough technology arrives.
So some jobs will get disrupted but I
think new even more valuable perhaps
more meaningful jobs will get created.
Um I think we're going to see this year
the beginnings of maybe impacting the
junior level entry level kind of jobs
internships this type of thing. I think
there is some evidence I can feel that
ourselves maybe like a slowdown in
hiring in that but I think that can be
more than compensated by the fact there
are these amazing creative tools out
there pretty much available for everyone
uh almost for free that if you know I
was to talk to a a class of undergrads
right now I would be telling them to get
really unbelievably proficient with
these tools I think to the extent that
even those of us building it we're so
busy building it it's hard to have also
time to really explore the almost the
capability overhang even today's models
and products have let alone tomorrow's
and I think that uh can be maybe better
than a traditional internship would have
been in terms of you sort of leaprogging
uh yourself to be a useful uh in a
useful in a profession so I think
there's that's what I see happening
probably probably in the next 5 years um
maybe we again slightly differ on time
scales on that but I think what happens
after AGI arrives that's a different
question because I think really we would
be in uncharted territory at that point
>> do you think it's going to take longer
than you thought last year when you said
half of all white color.
>> I have about the same view. I I actually
agree with you and with Deis that at the
time I made the comment there was no
impact on the labor market. I wasn't
saying there was an impact on the labor
market at that moment. Um you know now I
think maybe we're starting to see just
just the little beginnings of it you
know in software and coding. I even see
it within within anthropic where you
know it you know I can look forward I
can kind of look forward to a time where
on the more junior end and then on the
more on the more on the more on the more
intermediate end we actually need less
and not more people and you know we're
thinking about how to deal with that
within anthropic in a in a in a you know
sense in a sensible way. Um I you know
one to five years as of six months ago I
would stick with that. you know, if you
kind of, you know, connect this to what
I said before, which is, you know, we we
might have AI that's better than humans
at at everything in, you know, maybe one
to two years, maybe a little longer than
that. The those don't seem to line up.
The reason is that there's this there's
this lag and there's this replacement
thing, right? I I know that the labor
market is adaptable, right? It's just
like, you know, 80% of people used to do
farming. you know farming got automated
and then they became factory workers and
then knowledge workers. So, you know,
there is some level of adaptability here
as well, right? We should be
economically sophisticated about how the
labor market works. But my worry is as
this exponential keeps compounding and I
don't think it's going to take that long
again somewhere between between a year
and 5 years, it will overwhelm our
ability to adapt. I think I may be
saying the same thing Demis is just
factored out of that that difference we
have about timelines which I think
ultimately comes down to how how fast
you close the loop on CO and
>> how much confidence do you have that
governments get the scale of this and
have are beginning to think about what
policy responses they need to have
>> I don't think that that that it's
anywhere near enough work going on about
this I'm I'm constantly surprised even
when I meet economists at places like
this that they're not more of uh
professional economist, professors
thinking about what happens um and not
just sort of on the way to AGI but um
even if we get all the technical things
right that Dario is talking about and
the job displacement is one question
we're worried about the economics of
that but maybe there are ways to
distribute this new productivity this
new wealth more fairly I don't know if
we have the right institutions to do
that but that's what should happen at
that point there should be you know we
maybe in a post scarcity world but then
there are even the things that keep me
up right now there are even bigger
questions than that at that to do with
meaning and um purpose and a lot of the
things that we get from our jobs not
just economically that's one question
but I think that may be easier to solve
strangely than uh what happens to the
human condition and humanity as a whole
and I think I'm also optimistic we'll
come up with new answers there we do a
lot of things today um from extreme
sports to art that aren't necessarily
directly to do with economic gain so I
think we will find uh meaning and maybe
there'll be even more sort of
sophisticated versions of those
activities. Um, plus I think we'll be
exploring the stars. So, there'll be all
of that to to factor in as well for in
terms of purpose. But I think it's
really worth thinking now even on my
timelines of like 5 to 10 years away.
That isn't a lot of time uh before this
comes.
>> How big do you think is the risk of a
popular backlash against AI that will
somehow kind of cause governments to do
what from your perspective might be
stupid things? Because I'm just thinking
back to the era of you know
globalization in the 1990s when when
there was indeed some displacement of
jobs governments didn't do enough the
public backlash was such that we've
ended up sort of where we are now. Uh do
you think that there is a risk that
there will be a growing antipathy
towards what you are doing and your
companies in the kind of body politic?
>> Um I think there's definitely a risk. I
think um I think that's kind of
reasonable. there's fear and there's
worries about these things like jobs and
livelihoods. Um I think there's a couple
of things that I mean it's going to be
very complicated the next few years I
think geopolitically but also the
various factors here like we want to and
we're trying to do this with AlphaFold
and our science work and isomorphic our
spinout company solve all disease cure
diseases come up with new energy sources
I think as a society it's clear we'd
want that I think maybe the balance of
what the industry is doing is not enough
balance towards those types of
activities I think we should have a lot
more examples I know Dario agrees me of
like alphafold like things that help
sort of unequivocal good in the world.
And I think actually it's incumbent on
the industry and and all of us leading
players to show that more, demonstrate
that, not just talk about it, but
demonstrate that. Um and but then it's
going to come with these other intendent
disruptions and um but I don't I think
the other issue is the geopolitical
competition. There's obviously
competition between the companies, but
also US and China primarily. So unless
there's an international cooperation or
or understanding around this um uh which
I think would be good actually in terms
of things like minimum safety standards
for deployment I think Dario would agree
on that as well I think it's vitally
needed this technology is going to be
crossber border it's going to affect
everyone it's going to affect all of
humanity um actually contact is one of
my favorite films as well so funnily
enough I didn't realize it was yours too
Dario but I I think um um you know those
kind of things need to be worked through
um and and if we can maybe it would be
good to have a bit of slow a slightly
slower pace than we're currently
predicting even my timelines so that we
can get this right society but it that
would require some coordination that is
I prefer your timelines. Yes, [laughter]
I battle concede.
>> But but Dario, let's turn to this now
because the one thing since we last
spoke uh in Paris, the geopolitical
environment has, if anything, I don't
know, complicated, mad, crazy, whatever,
whatever phrase you want to use.
Secondly, the US has a very different
approach now towards China. It's a much
more it's a kind of no holds bar, go as
fast as we can, but then sell chips to
China. Um, and that is it. So, you've
got a different attitude towards the
United States. you've got a a very um
strange relationship between the United
States and and Europe right now
geopolitically against that I mean I
hear you talk about it would be nice to
have a CERN like organization I mean
it's a million years from where we are
from the real world so in the real world
have the geopolitical risks increased
and what if anything do you think should
be done about that and and the
administration seems to be doing the
opposite of what you were suggesting
>> yeah I mean look you know we're we're
we're just trying to do the best we can
to you know we're just we're just one
company and we're we're trying to
operate in, you know, the the
environment that exists, no matter how
no matter how crazy it is. But, you
know, I think I think at least my policy
recommendations haven't changed that,
you know, not selling chips is one of
the, you know, one of the one of the
biggest things we can do um to, you
know, make sure that we have the time to
handle this. Um, you know, you know, I
said I said before, you know, I I I
prefer Demis' timeline. I wish we had 5
to 10 years, you know. So, it's it's
possible he's just right and I'm just
wrong. But but assume I'm right and it
can be done in one to two years. Why
can't we slow down to to Demis'
timeline?
>> Well, no. The but but but the reason the
reason we the reason we can't do that is
is, you know, because we have
>> geopolitical adversaries building the
same technology at a similar pace. It's
very hard to have an enforcable
agreement where they slow down and we
slow down and and so if we can just if
we can just not sell the chips then this
isn't a question of competition between
the US and China. This is a question of
competition between me and Demis which
I'm very confident that we can work out.
>> And what do you make of the logic of the
administration which as I understand it
is we need to sell them chips because we
need to bind them into US supply chains.
So you know it's it's I I think it's I
think it's a question not just of time
scale but of the significance of the
technology right if this was telecom or
something then all this stuff about
proliferating the US stack and you know
wanting to build our you know chips
around the world to make sure that you
know you know this c you know the you
know these random countries in different
parts of the world you know build data
centers that have NVIDIA chips instead
of Huawei chips. You know, I think of
this more as like, you know, it's a
decision. Are we going to, you know,
sell nuclear weapons to North Korea and,
you know, because that produces some
profit for Boeing. Um, you know, where
where we can say, okay, yeah, these
cases were made by Boeing. Like, the US
is winning. Like, this is great. Like, I
I I just, you know, that that analogy
should just make clear how I see this
trade-off that I just don't think it
makes sense. Um and and we've done a lot
of more aggressive stuff toward you know
toward towards towards China China and
other players that that I think is much
less effective than this this one this
one measure.
>> One more area for me and then I hope
we'll have time for a question or two.
The other area of potential risk that
doomers worry about is a kind of all
powerful malign AI. Um, and I think
you've both been somewhat skeptical of
the doomer approach, but in the last
year we have seen, you know, these
models showing themselves to be capable
of deception, duplicity. Uh, do you
think that do you think differently
about that risk now than you did a year
ago? And is there something about the
way the models are evolving that we
should put a little bit more concern on
that?
>> Yeah, I mean, you know, since since the
beginning of Enthropic, we've kind of
thought about this risk. I mean you know
our our our research at the beginning of
it was very theoretical right you know
we pioneered this idea of mechanistic
interpretability which is looking inside
the model and and trying to understand
looking inside its brain trying to
understand why it does what it does as
it you know as as human neuroscientists
which we actually both have background
in um try try to understand try to
understand the brain and I think as time
has gone on we've we've increasingly
documented the you know bad behaviors of
the models when they emerge and are now
working on trying to address them with
mechanistic interpretability. So I you
know I think uh you know I I've always
been concerned about these these risks.
I've talked to Demis many times. I think
he has also been um concerned about
these risks. I think I have definitely
been and I I I would guess Demis as well
although I'll let him speak for himself
skeptical of of dumerism which is you
know we're doomed there's nothing we can
do or this is the most likely outcome. I
think this is a risk. This is a risk
that if we work all work together, we
can address. We can learn through
science to properly, you know, control
and and direct these creations that
we're building. But if we build them
poorly, if we go, you know, if if if
we're all racing and we go so fast that
there's no guard rails, then I think
there is risk of something going wrong.
So I'm going to give you a chance to
answer that in the context of of a
slightly broader question which is over
the past year have you grown more
confident of the upside potential of the
technology science all of the areas that
you have talked about a lot or are you
more worried about the risks that we've
been discussing
as I've been working on this for 20 plus
years so we we already knew the reason
I've spent my whole career on AI is is
the upsides of solving basically the
ultimate tool for science and
understanding the universe around us.
I've I've sort of been obsessed with
that since a kid and and and building AI
is the you know should be the ultimate
tool for that if we do it in the right
way. The risks also we've been thinking
about since the start at least the start
of deep mind 15 years ago and um we kind
of sort of foraw that if you got the
upsides it's a dual purpose technology
so it could be repurposed by say bad
actors for harmful ends. So we've needed
to think about that all the way through
but I'm a big believer in human
ingenuity. Um but the question is having
the time and the focus and all the best
minds collaborating on it to solve these
problems. I'm sure if we had that we
would solve the technical risk problem.
It maybe we don't have that and then
that will introduce risk because we'll
be sort of it'll be fragmented. There'll
be different projects and people be
racing each other then it's much harder
to make sure you know these systems that
we produce will be technically safe. But
I I feel like that's a very tractable uh
problem if we have the time.
>> If you if we have the time I want to
make sure there's one question,
gentlemen, keep it very short because
we've got literally two minutes.
>> Thanks. Hello.
>> Yeah. No speak.
>> Uh thanks very much. I'm Philip,
co-founder of Star Cloud Building Data
Centers in space. Um I wanted to ask a
slightly philosophical core question.
The sort of strongest argument for
doomerism to me is the Fermy paradox,
the idea that we don't see intelligent
life in our galaxy. I was wondering if
you guys have any thoughts. I've thought
a lot about that. That can't be the
reason because we we we should see all
the AIS that have so just everyone know
the idea is well it's sort of unclear
why that would happen, right? So if if
the reason there's a Fmy paradox there
are no aliens cuz they get taken out by
their own technology. We should be
seeing paper clips coming towards us
from some part of the galaxy and
apparently we don't. We don't see any
structures Dyson spheres nothing whether
they're AI or natur or sort of
biological. So to me um there has to be
a different answer to firming powders. I
have my own theories about that but it's
out of scope for the next minute but um
you know I I just feel like uh that that
I my prediction my feeling is that we're
past the great filter. It was probably
multisellular life if I would have to
guess. It was incredibly hard for for
biology to evolve that. Um so we're on
you know there isn't a comfort of like
what's going to happen next. I think
it's for us to write as humanity what's
going to happen next.
>> This this could be a great discussion
but is out of scope for the next 36
sessions. But what isn't 15 seconds each
what when we meet again I hope next year
uh the three of us which I would love uh
what will have changed by then
>> I well I think the biggest thing to
watch is this issue of AI systems
building AI systems how that goes whe
that whether that goes one way or
another that that will determine you
know whether it's a few more years until
we get there or or if we have you know
you know if if we have wonders and and a
great emergency in front of us that we
have to face.
>> AI systems, building air system.
>> I agree on that. So, we're we're keeping
close touch about that. Um but also I
think um outside of that, I think there
are other interesting uh uh uh ideas
being researched like world models,
continual learning. These are the things
I think that will need to be cracked. If
self-improvement doesn't sort of deliver
the goods on its own, then we'll need
these other things to work. And then I
think things like robotics may have its
sort of breakout moment. But but maybe
on the basis of what you've just said,
we should all be hoping that it does
take you a little bit longer and indeed
everybody else to give us
>> I would prefer that. I think that would
be better for the world.
>> Well, you guys could do something about
that. Thank you both very much.
[laughter]
[applause]
Heat. Heat.
[music]
>> [music]